# PHILIP BROWNE

 • Washington DC/Baltimore | ☐ (443) 459-7382 | ☑ pbrowne@gmail.com | ♠ PhilipBrowne | Im PhilipBrowneTech | ∰ www.philiprowne.com

Full Stack Software Engineer with a passion for helping people through technology and finding ways to efficiently and collaboratively solve problems. Dedicated and detail-oriented professional with a background of more than a decade as an orchestral musician and a proven record of success in multiple industries.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Go/Golang

Libraries/Frameworks/Protocols: Bootstrap, jQuery, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Flask, REST, GraphQL, Protocol Buffers,

gRPC, Selenium

Databases: SQL (PostgreSQL, SQLite, MySQL), MongoDB, ElasticSearch, Neo4j, DynamoDB

Testing: Jasmine, Jest, React Test Library, PyTest

CI/CD & Deployment: Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, Azure, Google Cloud Platform, Jenkins, GitHub, GitLab

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### Voter Info / Repository Link

2021

Full-Stack Voter Information Application using Google Civic Information, EasyPost, and MapQuest APIs

Technologies Used: JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, AJAX, Axios, Python, Flask, Bcrypt, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL

## Space Force / Repository Link

2021

- Full-Stack Platform Game developed for Mintbean.io Hiring Hackathon built with PhaserJS Library. Mintbean Star Award Winner for "exemplary achievement in the field of web development"
- Technologies Used: JavaScript, PhaserJS, JavaScript State Machine, Bootstrap, Python, Flask, Bcrypt, SQLAlchemy PostgreSQL

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Backend Software Engineer**

2022 - Present

Megaport

- Develop back-end services using modern development practices and technology stacks including Go and gRPC.
- Work closely with Product Teams and UX designers to create APIs consumable by Front-End Developers.
- Manage Cloud Native software deployments to multiple cloud providers including Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud, and Microsoft Azure.

Full Stack Developer 2021

M-Partners Incorporated

 Developed and maintained both independent and collaborative projects for small startup specializing in new concepts in data analytics, artificial intelligence, and machine learning to enable automatic end-to-end data collection, processing, and analysis.

• Built scalable and highly reliable products and maintained uptime of existing applications.

Freelance Musician

2009 - Present

 Professional Orchestral French Horn player with experience working with groups such as the Baltimore Symphony, Virginia Symphony, Richmond Symphony, Pittsburgh Opera, and National Philharmonic, among others.

## **EDUCATION**

Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Maryland

Graduated with BM in 2009, GPD in 2012

Bachelor of Music, French Horn Performance; Graduate Performance Diploma (GPD), French Horn Performance

Yale University Graduate School of Music

2012-2014

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track Fellowship

2021

An 800-hour fellowship that covers key aspects of front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms. Modules include learning resources, practice exercises, projects, and career-related coursework.